thejockeyclub.co.uk 2019-07-04

# Privacy Policy | The Jockey Club

Oops, your browser is out of date - Please [upgrade your browser](http://browsehappy.com/) to improve your experience.

The Jockey Club (“we”, “our”, “us”) takes your privacy very seriously.

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully to see how we will treat the personal information that you provide to us whether you are a visitor to one of our websites listed below (the “ **Site** ”), a user of one of our applications (the " **App** ") or our Wi-Fi or a visitor to one of our venues, events or festivals as listed below.

For the purpose of data protection laws, the data controller(s) of any personal information collected on the Site or at a venue, event or festival are listed below.

This Privacy Policy provides information to you about the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us, whether you are a visitor to our Site, user of the App or Wi-Fi or a visitor to one of our venues, events or festivals. This Privacy Policy shall be read in conjunction with our Cookies Policy any notices or terms located within our venues and our Site terms and conditions. We will take reasonable care to keep your information secure and to prevent any unauthorised access or use of it. We process all information in accordance with applicable UK data protection legislation. We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time and the change will take effect once the revised Privacy Policy is available on the Site and/or App. Therefore, please refer to this Policy each time you submit your personal information. Any changes to our Privacy Policy will be posted to the Site and, where appropriate, will be notified to you via email.  
By using, registering or placing an order on the Site, or at one of our venues, events or festivals, or using our App or Wi-Fi, we may use and transfer your information under the terms of this Policy.

###   
ARE YOU AGED 14 OR UNDER?

If you are aged 14 or under, please get your parent/guardian's permission beforehand whenever you provide personal information to us. Users without this consent are not allowed to provide us with personal information.

### ARE YOU A SOLE TRADER / PARTNERSHIP OR AN INDIVIDUAL COMMUNICATING WITH US FROM A BUSINESS?

Where we collect and use your personal data from a corporate perspective (i.e. where we are contracting with you as a sole trader or partnership, or contracting with the business you are employed/contracted by) this will be done in accordance with the relevant parts of this Privacy Policy. If you have any questions or concerns about this, please contact us using either the details set out below or by speaking with your usual contact at The Jockey Club.

###   
INFORMATION WE MAY COLLECT FROM YOU

**The information you provide to us**

We may ask you to provide information to us or collect information from you on different occasions, such as when you:

  * email enquiries, contributions or your views to us;
  * enter competitions;
  * submit a job application, including completing the requisite diversity form;
  * use the Wi-Fi at any of our venues;
  * register to use our Site or App and/or receive or download information or documentation;
  * register for our rewards programme, 'Rewards4Racing';
  * subscribe to our newsletters or mailing list; or
  * purchase goods or services from us, including memberships.

In some instances the provision of information will be mandatory, for example if you purchase goods or services from us, otherwise you will be able to choose whether or not to disclose your personal information or not.

The information you give us may include your name, address, date of birth, gender, e-mail address, user name and password, phone number, financial and credit card information, demographic information such as postcode, preferences and interests, feedback regarding our Site, App, Wi-Fi, venues, events or festivals and other information relevant to customer surveys or offers. We may also collect and process CCTV images, records of any correspondence and communications with us and telephone calls may also be recorded.  
Please note that we have the ability to retain your contact details should you input them on our Site using VeCapture by Ve Interactive, even if you do not complete your registration/transaction/quote by clicking submit. Such contact details may be used to contact you to assist with your registration/transaction, where you have consented to this.

####   
The information we collect about you

We may also collect information about each of your visits to the Site, our Wi-Fi or use of our App in particular we may automatically collect the following information: (i) technical information, including the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet, MAC addresses, traffic data, location data, your login information, browser type and version, time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and cookies which will be collected in accordance with our Cookies Policy and

(ii) information about your visit, including the full Uniform Resource Locators (URL) clickstream to, through and from the Site or App (including date and time); products you viewed or searched for; page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), and methods used to browse away from the page and any phone number used to call our customer service number.

#### Information we receive from other sources

Personal information may also be provided to us from online vendors, service providers who refer you to our Sites, App or services, from customer lists lawfully acquired from third party vendors and from other third parties who work with us in connection with our Sites, App or services. Third-party service providers may, without limitation, be appointed to provide technical support, process your transactions and maintain your accounts or to run promotions or marketing campaigns. We may have access to any personal information provided to such vendors, service providers and third party e-commerce services.

### HOW THE JOCKEY CLUB USES YOUR INFORMATION

We may use your personal information for the following purposes:   
**Information you give to us**

We will use this information:

  * to provide customer support e.g. responding to your enquiries;
  * to send you a welcome email to verify your account when you register with us or make a purchase and other emails for the purposes of providing any services, products, competitions or promotions to you, including in relation to account management or system maintenance;
  * to ask you to complete surveys in respect of your experience with us (for example, in relation to catering), which you can choose to complete or not;
  * [to allocate "points" which will remain inactive unless or until you are a registered member of Rewards4Racing];
  * to process job applications and diversity data;
  * to send information to you that you have requested;
  * to notify you about changes to our services and/or products;
  * to carry out our obligations arising from any contract that we may enter into with you including to process and fulfil any order or request;
  * for statistical and research purposes;
  * to provide you with marketing information about other services or products we offer that are the same or similar to those that you have already purchased, or services or products you have consented to receiving. If you do not wish to receive this information please use the unsubscribe function in the information we send you, update your preferences through the preference centre or alternatively write to the Data Protection Officer at the address above;
  * for internal record keeping;
  * to improve our products and services;
  * to carry out appropriate and necessary investigations and identity checks and discharge our legal and regulatory obligations and duties, including to comply with anti-fraud and anti-money laundering requirements;
  * to ensure that content from the Site, App and/or Wi-Fi is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer or device (as applicable).
  * If you have selected Secure Delivery for tickets. We may send you a notification of the dispatch of your order via our postal partner. This SMS or Email will allow you to to track your item. 

_Please note we will not use any financial or credit card information for any purpose other than to discharge our legal/regulatory duties and to process payments paid by you for our products and services or due to you by agreement (e.g. refunds)._

We, our holding, subsidiary and sister companies and selected third parties (such as our commercial partners) would like to send you marketing information, by post, e-mail, or SMS. Please see the "consent" section of **USING YOUR INFORMATION IN ACCORDANCE WITH DATA PROTECTION LAWS** below. If you change your mind about what marketing you would like to receive from us or third parties (including our commercial partners) at any time, you can unsubscribe via the link in any marketing communication, update your preferences through your account preference centre or alternatively can write to the Data Protection Officer at the address below or email us at [DPO@thejockeyclub.co.uk](mailto:DPO@thejockeyclub.co.uk).

If you submit your views to us electronically or otherwise we may circulate them internally for training and management purposes. We may also publish your views on the Site, App or in other media. If you do not want us to do this, please let us know when you submit your views.  
We may aggregate the information you send to us with other data (so that you cannot be identified from that data) and use that aggregated data for administrative purposes.

####   
Information we collect about you

We will use this information:

  * to administer our Site, App and/or Wi-Fi and for internal operations, including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes;
  * to carry out appropriate and necessary investigations and identity checks and discharge our legal and regulatory obligations and duties, including to comply with anti-fraud and anti-money laundering requirements, and (where applicable) to safeguard our staff and other customers / users in respect of unlawful, disruptive or objectionable behaviour at any of our
  * venues, events or festivals or on our Site, App or Wi-Fi;
  * to improve our Site, App and/or Wi-Fi to ensure that content is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer or device;
  * to enhance our Site, App and/or Wi-Fi to ensure you receive a continuously improving customer service;
  * to allow you to participate in interactive features of our Site or App, when you choose to do so;
  * as part of our efforts to keep our Site, App, Wi-Fi, venues, events and festivals safe and secure;
  * for data-matching purposes in respect of your use of our Site, App or services and your use of certain third party services;
  * to deliver (whether directly or indirectly via third parties) effective and personalised marketing material and content of The Jockey Club and where you have consented, other companies within our Group and to assist us in the improvement and optimisation of advertising, marketing material and content, our services and the Sites, App and/or Wi-Fi;
  * to measure, understand or monitor the effectiveness of advertising, promotions, marketing material and content and any joint initiatives with our affiliates, suppliers, partners, subcontractors and other selected third parties;
  * to measure or understand the effectiveness of advertising we serve to you and others, and to deliver relevant advertising to you where permitted; and/or
  * to make suggestions and recommendations to you and other users of our Site or services about goods or services that may interest you or them.

#### Information we receive from other sources

We will combine this information with information you give to us and information we collect about you. We will use this information and the combined information for the purposes set out above (depending on the types of information we receive).

### USING YOUR INFORMATION IN ACCORDANCE WITH DATA PROTECTION LAWS

Data protection laws require that we meet certain conditions before we are allowed to use your data in the manner described in this Privacy Policy. We take our responsibilities under data protection laws extremely seriously, including meeting these conditions. To use your personal data, we will rely on the following conditions, depending on the activities we are carrying out:

  * **Compliance with legal obligations:** As an entity established under the laws of England and Wales, The Jockey Club is obliged to comply with UK laws and guidance provided by UK regulatory bodies. In particular, we will need to process your personal information to verify your identity, in some circumstances establish your age, establish your source of funds for anti-money laundering, anti-terrorism and fraud purposes, and to establish whether you have been barred from any of our venues or from using our Site due to objectionable behaviour. You will not be able to object to processing or ask for the deletion of your personal information insofar as it falls under this category.
  * **Necessary for the entry into** / **performance of a contract:** When you enter into a transaction with us, a contract between you and us will have been entered into. In order for us to fulfil our obligations under such contract (e.g. to allow you to purchase a ticket or membership from us), we will need to collect and process your personal information. Failure to provide the requisite personal information on sign-up and financial information on entering into the transaction or objecting to this type of processing/exercising your deletion rights will unfortunately mean we cannot provide our goods/services to you.
  * **Consent:** We may send you electronic marketing messages about us and our venues, events and offers where you have not unsubscribed and where you have purchased tickets to our venues or events or bought goods or other services from us. We provide easy ways to stop our marketing, and you can opt out at any time.

If you are not a customer of ours but have provided us with consent to use your details for marketing purposes, then we may also contact you about our events, goods and services.   
If you have confirmed that you would like to hear from us about other party’s goods and services then we will use your details to contact you with marketing information about such party's goods and services.   
If you have confirmed that you would like to hear directly from a third party (including other members of our Group) about such party’s goods and services then we will share your details with such third party so they can contact you about their goods and services.   
In each of the situations above, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time and can object to processing of this nature.

  * **Legitimate interests:** To use your personal data for any other purpose described in this Privacy Policy, we will rely on a condition known as "legitimate interests". It is in our legitimate interests to collect your personal data as it provides us with the information that we need to provide our services to you more effectively and to manage our business. Effectively, this requires us to carry out a balancing test of our interests in using your personal data (for example, in order to provide you with the information, products and services that you request from us), against the interests you have as a citizen and the rights you have under data protection laws (for example, to not have your data sold to third party marketing companies without your knowledge, or not store your personal data in insecure or unstable countries or regions). As a result of our balancing test, which is detailed below, we have determined, acting reasonably and considering the circumstances, that we are able to process your personal data in accordance with the data protection laws on the basis that we have a legitimate business interest.  

    * We have a legitimate interest in processing your personal data as: (a) We need the information to respond to your enquiries (and where relevant process your CV/ job application); (b) We need the information to be able to send you information; and (c) We would be unable to provide our products and/or services without processing your information.
    * Necessity: We consider that it is reasonable for us to process your personal data for the purposes of our legitimate interests outlined above as we process your personal data only so far as is necessary for such purpose.
    * Impact: We consider that it is reasonable for us to process your personal data for the purposes of our legitimate interests outlined above as it can be reasonably expected for us to process your personal information in this way for the purposes set out above. In most cases the information is being processed for your benefit as well as ours.

###   
HOW LONG WE KEEP YOUR INFORMATION FOR

When your data is no longer required for the purposes listed above, we will delete it within the periods set out below:

  * Where a customer has purchased a product or service .eg. a ticket, marketing consents will be refreshed after 5 years and data deleted after a further period of 12 months;
  * We may keep your personal information beyond 7 years, in transactional platforms to maintain transactional record completeness to enable us to retain the information we may require for legal, regulatory and anti-fraud purposes.
  * Where a subscriber (being an individual who has not purchased a ticket, but has subscribed to marketing), marketing consents will be refreshed after 24 months and data deleted after a further period of 12 months.
  * Marketing emails and other communications where possible will typically be deleted after 5 years;
  * Call recordings will typically be deleted after 24 months;
  * CCTV will typically be deleted after 90 days;
  * Unsuccessful job applications will typically be deleted after 12 months.

We may keep your personal information for up to 7 years, to enable us to retain the information we may require for legal and regulatory purposes.  
We may keep your personal information for an amount of time which is different to that stated above, in certain circumstances. Where this is the case, you will be supplied with a supplemental policy or privacy statement, which will explain the relevant retention periods to you.

###   
SHARING INFORMATION

We may disclose your personal information to any member of our Group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 1159 of the UK Companies Act 2006 (our " **Group** ").  
We will only share your personal information with our affiliates and the third party service providers if this is necessary or reasonably required for any of the purposes listed above. Such third party service providers are not entitled to use your information for their own purposes.   
We will only disclose your information to:

  * business partners, suppliers and sub-contractors for the performance of any contract we enter into with them or you;
  * members of the Group and third party suppliers and service providers for the purposes listed under **HOW THE JOCKEY CLUB USES YOUR INFORMATION** above;
  * third party suppliers and service providers to the extent they assist the Group with its legal/regulatory obligations e.g. providers of services in respect of anti-money laundering, fraud, verification etc. In particular we share your information with SEE Group Limited, Groups on Track Limited and Racing Breaks Ltd through our ticketing platform for fraud prevention;
  * members of the Group and selected commercial partners so that they can contact you with details of the services that they provide, where you have expressly opted-in/consented to the disclosure of your personal data for these purposes (see "consent" under **USING YOUR INFORMATION IN ACCORDANCE WITH DATA PROTECTION LAWS** above:
  * [Rewards4Racing where you hold an account with them, in order for your points to be collected/ validated];
  * analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and optimisation of our Site, App and/or Wi-Fi and other selected third parties; and
  * your employer, educational institution (e.g. school, college or university), email or internet provider, parents (if you are under the age of 18) or law enforcement agencies, or other appropriate third parties, where we consider your behaviour to be unlawful, offensive, inappropriate or objectionable at one of our venues, events or festivals or on our Site, App or Wi-Fi.

We will disclose your personal information to third parties:

  * in the event that we consider selling or buying any business or assets or merge or enter into a joint venture with another business entity in which case we will disclose your personal data to any prospective sellers or buyers of such business or assets;
  * in the event of any insolvency situation (e.g. the administration or liquidation) of The Jockey Club or any of its Group;
  * if we, or substantially all of our assets, are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by us about our customers will be one of the transferred assets;
  * in order to enforce or apply our Site, Wi-Fi, App, venue, festival or event terms and conditions;
  * to protect the rights, property, or safety of us, our staff, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations (including without limitation, other third parties, your employer, educational institution, email or internet provider, your parents (if you are under the age of 18) and/or the metropolitan police or other law enforcement agencies) for the purposes of staff and customer safety (whether this is in-store or online), crime prevention, fraud protection and credit risk reduction; and
  * if we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation or regulatory requirements, or otherwise for the prevention or detection of fraud or crime

Please note that some of these third parties may be located outside of the United Kingdom, including in countries where data protection laws might not exist or be of a lower standard than the EU. Those parties may process information, fulfil and deliver orders, process credit card payments and provide services on our behalf. By submitting your personal information, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If you wish to opt out of this, please email [DPO@thejockeyclub.co.uk](mailto:DPO@thejockeyclub.co.uk).

### Where we store your personal data

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us, our Group or for one of our suppliers. This includes staff engaged in, among other things, the provision of support services. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers, or those of our suppliers. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our Site, App or Wi-Fi, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our Site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

####   
LINKS

The Site, App or Wi-Fi may contain links to other sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of external sites. We encourage our users to be aware when you visit third party sites (including for the avoidance of doubt social media sites, such as Facebook, Twitter, Instagram and/or Snapchat and partner sites (for example, Rewards4Racing)) and to read the privacy statements applicable on those sites/apps. This Privacy Policy does not apply to information collected on third parties’ sites/apps.

#### YOUR RIGHTS

You have a number of rights under data protection law in relation to the way we process your personal data, although these are not absolute and in some instances we may be unable to accept your request, in which case we will respond to you to explain why. These are set out **below**. You may contact us using the details on our Site (or by contacting us directly – details **below** ) to exercise any of these rights and we will respond to any request received from you within one month from the date of the request.

Our Data Protection Officer can be contacted by email at [DPO@thejockeyclub.co.uk](mailto:DPO@thejockeyclub.co.uk). Please address any questions, comments and requests regarding our data processing practices to us in this way in the first instance.

If you have any concerns regarding our processing of your personal data, or are not satisfied with our handling of any request by you in relation to your rights, you also have the right to make a complaint to the Information Commissioner's Office. Their address is:

**First Contact Team**  
 **Information Commissioner's Office**  
 **Wycliffe House**  
 **Water Lane**  
 **Wilmslow**  
 **SK9 5AF**

### Rewards4Racing

Rewards4Racing is our recommended rewards and loyalty programme which is free for all our customers to join and use. As a Rewards4Racing member, you will be entitled to earn Rewards4Racing points when you purchase tickets, raceday packages and hospitality packages at any of The Jockey Club’s 15 racecourses. 

**New Members –** if you choose to opt-in to Rewards4Racing when you purchase an advanced ticket (online or by phone) with us, an account will be created with the programme for free using the details (including name, address and email address) that you use on your account with us. Please note that you will need to set a password separately with Rewards4Racing. Once you join the programme, the information relating to your transaction (including the number of tickets or packages purchased and the total price paid) will be processed by Rewards4Racing for the purposes of applying points to your Rewards4Racing account. Please look out for your Rewards4Racing welcome email so that you can activate your account and start saving towards your next purchase with us.

**Existing Members –** as an existing Rewards4Racing member, following an advanced ticket purchase (online or by phone) with us, the information relating to your transaction (including the number of tickets or packages purchased, the total price paid and any Rewards4Racing points redeemed as part of your transaction) will be processed by Rewards4Racing for the purposes of applying points to, or removing points from, your Rewards4Racing account.

**How Rewards4Racing will use your information:**

**To provide member benefits -** if you are a customer who is a member of the Rewards4Racing programme, we will share with Rewards4Racing information concerning your transactions with us. The information we share will be used by Rewards4Racing to provide you with member benefits and to operate the Rewards4Racing programme. For more information on how Rewards4Racing will use your information please see its privacy notice, which can be viewed [here](https://www.rewards4racing.com/privacy). Where we share your information in this way, we are not responsible for Rewards4Racing or how it uses your information as a member of the Rewards4Racing programme.

For further details about the Rewards4Racing programme view [Rewards4Racing’s full terms and conditions](https://www.rewards4racing.com/terms).

Should you wish to opt-out of the Rewards4Racing programme, you may do so at any time by contacting Rewards4Racing by email at [hello@rewards4racing.com](mailto:hello@rewards4racing.com).

**As a service provider to us -** from time to time, we ask Rewards4Racing to help us look at improvements to the way in which we engage with our customers. This includes making recommendations to help customers save money on their ticket purchases, providing the tools to help us incentivise customers to come to one of our racedays or improving their experience at one of our racecourses. In providing these services, we may disclose transactional information to Rewards4Racing about our customers (who may not be Rewards4Racing members) so that Rewards4Racing may analyse transactional information, customer purchases and behaviours (and trends) as well as segmenting our customer database. For the purposes of performing these tasks, we continue to control any information shared - Rewards4Racing acts under our instruction and as a data processor only and will not use your personal information for its own purposes.

### UPDATING YOUR INFORMATION WITH THE JOCKEY CLUB

In the event that there is a change to your personal information, for example your contact details, please let us know of this by (a) updating your preferences through your account preference centre or (b) writing to the Data Protection Officer, at the address provided below so that we can keep your information up to date and accurate.

### CONTACT US

If you have any comments or queries about this Privacy Policy, wish to stop direct marketing by The Jockey Club or its holding, subsidiary or sister companies or you wish to exercise any of your rights set out above please write to our Data Protection Officer at The Jockey Club, 75 High Holborn, London, WC1V 6LS or email [DPO@thejockeyclub.co.uk](mailto:DPO@thejockeyclub.co.uk).

This Policy was last reviewed and updated: November 2018
